Let's go to the next subject which
is interface development, okay?  And
in interface development, well,
the other day we're going to see, we were
working with, let's see,
ah, let's see, let's see where we are.
Descriptive languages, okay?  That we
were working with CSS,
components.  Ah, very good.  Okay,
components, features and fields of
application.  There is nothing at the moment.
We're going to link components with, look,
join data types.  Okay, well,
we've done this.  Associations of
actions to events.  Okay, let's go to
events.
Well, it is
mandatory that Perfect, Fran.  Now,
now when I get back from this class I'll do
another review, okay?  It's essential that
we review the events
available in JavaScript, the language par
excellence for creating
user interfaces in web environments
.  So for that, editing
the code generated by
design objects, right?  And classes, properties and
methods, right?  And listening events,
no.  Okay, wait
a minute,
because we're going to get started on this in a bit
.
I'm going to do one thing.  I'm going to do
something
in class today.  I'm going to break
the order a little, it's okay because we'll
come back here later.  Let's go with
natural user interfaces, shall we?  We'll
go back to unit one and
talk about natural interfaces, okay?
A natural interface is one that
in principle speaks the same language as
the human being.  In this case, both in
Python and JavaScript, we go in this
case to JavaScript, we have eh APIs that
allow us to work, allow us to
collaborate with an e, how would I say?
With a natural interface.  Let's go
for it.  I come here and 101 or 001
voice and speech synthesis voice pun html.   I
don't know if you guys can hear the
audio, okay?  But nothing happens.
Now now we will see.  Okay, so
let's get to it.  Let's see
Chrome here.
Okay, so there's a very simple API here
which is Webkit speech sample
demo Spanish.
So the webkit speech might mean I have to
use Chrome instead of Chromium,
but that's fine.
Well, for example, any browser
based on Webkit depends on
this Google API. That also has to be
said, and you know that
I don't like dependency at all,
but
okay, this is very nice, but I don't
want to make it as
simple as possible.  Mother of God of
beautiful love, uncle.  Where are you going?   I
mean, I was doing a really
cool demo, but of course, I don't want this,
we'll use it really cool later, you
know?  But
no, no is no no
no.  Let's see.   No
no.  Uh, simplest possible demo of speech
synthesis,
because it's making me a
complete application that seems
fantastic to me, but it's not what I
want.  Okay, the first thing I want you to
see is Venga.
Okay,
okay, fantastic.  Okay, come on, let's go
for it.  So, uh, talk button,
okay?  Pig Boys.  And above all, the
objective is this, above all, the objective
is for you to see that there is a
pre-built object in the browsers that is
speech synthesis and we are going to see what voices
we have.  Let's go for it.  I'm going to
local host
and uh I'm going to DAM, okay?  And the idea is
that you see that the
natural interfaces, which is what this
second section is about here and eh, still
and voice and speech.  Okay, talk, okay, and it'll
tell me and it'll tell me that since I'm on
Chromium, it'll tell me that I don't have to go to
Chrome for speech
synthesis to be applied.  Okay,
this is out of the moment.  This over here.
Okay, I do this and Okay.  Okay, you
don't hear it.  Okay, I'm going to put it so that it's
at least recorded in the
recording.
Hello, this is a
Spanish voice synthesis test.  Okay, now I think
you don't hear it, but when I believe, I
believe, but wait, wait,
maybe I'm wrong.
Speaker
lif computer audio.
Hey, I don't know what he's done now.
Au.  I don't know if you can hear me.  Can you hear me?
Can you hear me?  Can you hear me?
Oh, oh, oh.  RIP.  Okay.  Okay.  Okay, okay,
okay.  Come on,
let's see now.  Now you hear me
now.  Okay, so I don't know what I've done,
but what I want is,
let's see.
No, well it seems that it doesn't let me.  Okay,
no problem.  You will hear it
in the recording.  Okay,
so from here on, this is a
test that I do.   I
give him something to talk about.  This is a test I'm
doing.
And I don't know if you're seeing the
speaker volume there, okay?  He's
talking to us, let's say.
Very good.  Very good.  Well, from
here on, of course, what does this mean?
Well, websites can talk to us,
right?
Once once that Okay, okay,
okay, okay.  Once we have this,
we can also talk to the
web.  So new file 002 eh
microphone
and dot html.
Now, next I come over here and
I want, okay?  The eh now tiniest
of eh speech recognition.
and I'm going to make a
super mega dumb app that
will simply
repeat what I tell it back to me.  That's it.  Okay,
so we're coming this way, okay?  And
microphone.
And basically what's going to happen
is that if I come here and wait, I'm
going to the
voice synthesis folder.
Okay, I'm going to the microphone folder.
Allow.
This is a test
and there you have it, okay?  That is,
we have
the ability to
both listen and speak built into the browser.  Of course,
if what I do now is put the
two projects together, then I'm going to create a
small microweb where
I talk to it and the website responds to me.  Sure,
zero intelligence right now.  Okay,
so,
sure, that's what I'm saying.  That's what I'm
saying.  Exact.  Okay, so
far we've been communicating with the computer,
the mouse, and the keyboard, and
we'll probably continue to communicate
that way.  But that's the idea.  The idea is to
be able to talk to an application and have the
application, so to speak, understand you—
we'll talk about that later—and have the
application react, let's say, to what
you tell it.  Let's go for it and
now we'll do some testing, because I
want to delete a record, I want
whatever, even if it's just a small
demonstration.
Well, for that, Well, for that
we go to this.  Let's see.  Mm.  Mm.
Okay.  Okay, okay, okay.   Hear.
Okay.
And rec on result.
Yes, but no.
Okay, first of all I
don't understand myself.
That's the problem here.  Okay,
now every time
this is executed, this really pisses me off,
it's equal to function e
and it's that star operator that's
fine for one line, but of course, when
you have more than one line, things get
complicated, obviously,
and that's better.
So what happens?  Well, here in
the rec on result what I'm doing
is capturing the results and in the
result, okay?  Yes, yes, yes,
Michelangelo.  Let's see, at the moment I don't know
what I'm going to do, that is, I don't know what
guidelines I'm going to give him.  I'll
put some in, okay?  But with small
guidelines, with a small at least
a uh a interpret commands, okay?
For example, delete record two and that's
it.  and the program says, "Okay,
delete is that I'm going to commit a crime."
Record is what it's going to tell me or maybe I'll
tell you to delete five or add three.  Okay, that's
very much what you said, isn't it?  Little
guidelines.
Okay, so I come here
and now I bring 003, I merge
projects
and then we go there.  Let's see.
Led voices.
Okay, this over here.
Okay, okay.  Pig boys, this is staying.
The voices, this stays.
This stays.  This is
initial setup.
Initial configuration of the
voice synthesis eh.
Okay.  Come on, now on click.  No, no, no,
no.  Okay.  Okay.
V Pig Boys,
okay?  And value, this is what this
short.  No, I don't like
this horrible star operator.  Okay.  And
we'll see.
And now here.
Okay.  And the result,
okay?  First write
what you have heard and now
speak it.
And then instead of putting value, I'm going to
put this.
I'm going to put this.  Okay,
let's go.  Let's go there.
If this goes well,
if this goes well, every time there is a
result
we go to project three.  Okay,
this is a test.
This is a test.
And you didn't hear it, but it just
said to me, "This is a test, okay?
And this is another test.
And this is another test. And you didn't
hear it, but you'll see it in the
recording, but it responds to me. But
what does it respond with? Well, with the same thing
I told it. Okay, it's fine, it's
fine because the application is very
dumb. But if I now say delete
five,
delete five, be
careful. Okay, this is now
becoming a verb and a
direct object. What do I delete? And, I mean, sorry,
what am I going to do and what's
going to happen? Okay? I mean,
delete that element that has the
identifier five, for example.
Another thing I can do is
continuous listening, okay? But anyway, it doesn't matter.
So now what I'm
going to do next is create a small
data structure, okay? I'm going to
create a small table.
To do this, to do this, let's see. 004
eh, I paint table
point  html. Okay, so I say
initial data
and I say e clients is equal to an object.
Clients is an object, well, or not, or it's
a ray
that has objects.
Okay, so I say, uh, oh, sorry, I say
,
name is José Vicente,
uh, last name
is Carratalá Sánchez
and
email is equal to info@josvicente
and comom, okay?
ojocarsa.com
comma
and we're going to create three clients,
okay? And Juan
and Jorge
and I don't know, García
and López.
So if I have for example here
a container
divide container,
okay? Well now what I'm going to say is
that inside the container
I'm going to paint a table.
So function
paint table
is
LED string
is equal to table
eh
tr
th
1 2 three, I close TR and that's it. And this is
name,
last name
e and what and email. Okay, now, now
clients
dot for each
function client. I
go over
and say string plus equals
string plus equals what?
Well, PR.
TR
T
pum. And then I say client dot first
name comma client
dot last name comma  dot il client. And
finally, string plus equals we close,
okay? And then I say
documenty
selector container
[Music]
dot inner html is equal to string
and therefore it paints a table.
Let's see it.
If I run this, I paint a table or what happens
syntax invalid octed token. Let's
see what token I have.
Ah, very good. Something related to here.
Yes, I'm missing some quotes. Okay,
[Music]
no, neither.
Okay, what else am I missing? Yes, and I'm missing
more quotes. I'm,
I'm fine. Okay, come on, there we have
the table. Okay, now
what I want to do is delete, okay?
This is zero is one and this is two. It's
a ray.
So I come over here, I come over
here and I say and I say
eh 005, react react
goes to the voice
and then the voice
eh LED recognized
is equal to this
ae e of results of recognized.
Okay. And now I say and now I say
if.
if what is worth if recognized
dot split
of space of cer  It's the same.
If you want to give an operation,
it's equal to this here.
And I say switch operation
case delete
console.log let's delete
break.
As you can imagine,
case insert, case update,
case read.
Let's insert,
let's update,
let's read.
We execute
console in view. We
reload. I don't know if I'm on the latest
version.
Okay,
delete five.
Delete five.
And it says, let's delete. Insert
José Vicente
. Insert José Vicente.
And it says, let's insert. I say,
update four.
Update four.
And let's update.
This is what you were saying, Miguel Ángel,
which are some small guidelines,
okay? Very basic for now. Now
later we'll talk a little about the topic of
machine learning, tools for
automatic learning and we'll see
how we can do it and how, well, what
tools we have at our
disposal for Okay.
Okay, then,
then we'll go there. Okay,
drink a moment. My throat is
hurting. Absolutely.
Okay,
so in the case of delete
next
I say, of course, it recognizes it as a
letter,  Right? So I say, LED number
equals recognized split point of 1.
Of course, I make a switch
switch of number, I have no
choice because it recognizes it
as a string, okay? And I say case 1 or case
0,
well something's going to happen, okay? Case cer.
Let's see, let's see. Well look, I'm
telling you, clients
pun splies
of 0, 1
case pluncu, plunco, plunco, plunco and
plunco.
Case 1, clients one case two clients
two
case 3, clients 3,
case 4 clients 4 and case 5 clients 5 and
finally
draw a table.
Okay, attention. I'm
going to
delete one.
Delete one.
E, what happened? Hey, nice. What do you mean
? Ah, clients. No, it's not Hostias.
Clients it must be true. Clients
, clients, clients, clients, clients
. Okay, come on.
Delete one.
And it deleted it. Okay. And now I say
delete zero.
Delete zero.
And it deletes it. Okay, with which the
Idea, obviously this is very, very
primitive, okay? But the idea of ​​being able to
do this, the idea of ​​being able to execute
voice and speech synthesis is
precisely to be able to create, to be able to
build applications that recognize
voice and with which we can
communicate with voice.
Body part recognition is probably something quite a bit more complex, but for that we have libraries such as, for example, Media. Gosh, I've lost Media, but anyway, I have it in last year's exercises
. Just a moment.
Let's see,
Media Pipe. That's fine. Media Pipe.
Media Pipe. Simplest
JavaScript example hands.
Okay, in body parts and movements
. 001 hand recognition.
I insist that I'm going to use a
library here,
but I have no other choice,
okay? Because, uh, making a
voice recognition library too, okay?
Making a library for that would be a
pain. Let's see.
Obviously, we load the Media
Pipe library from a CDN, obviously.
Let's see. Okay. And let's go.
Okay. Mm. Okay,
okay,  Okay, okay. Okay,
here we go. Paste,
execute. Okay, we're loading. I hope
the CDNs are active.
And here we go. Uh, I'm going here, I'm going
here. Parent
and non-parent and
parts body movements and
exercises and recognition. Okay, if
everything goes well, a
moment here. Okay, good. If everything is good.
Oh, a hand. Okay, so I have a hand.
This media pipe library is great
because Oh, it recognizes a hand in my
eye. What a strange thing. Okay, it's great
because it allows us to recognize
body parts and allows us, okay, to do
things. to do things like what. In
fact, if you look closely, the recognition
even in hidden areas is quite
cool. It vibrates a little, but it's quite
cool. The important thing about this is that
when we use the media pipe
002 library,
access to the data,
well, I, for example, can come
here. Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay,
okay. Okay,
let's see. Draw connectors. Draw
Landmarks. Okay,
a moment. Yes, but  Here Landmarks, this
is what I want. Console.log
Landmarks
and the landmarks
I can lower the radius, by the way,
okay? And the landmarks
are the data. Okay, there's nothing, but
I do it like this
and I don't know if you see. I'm going to remove my
hand. As the positions
of each of the points appear in X, in Y,
in Z. So from there I
can program that if I close my
fist, then I don't know what happens, if I open my
fist, then I don't know what happens. If I raise
a finger, then I don't know what happens. Okay, but
it doesn't end here. It doesn't end
here. It's much cooler.
Now. Eh, tiniest example of face
eh recognition
eh boundaries
admes.
Okay, and now you're going to freak out. In my
case there's a small problem and that is that I
have a beard and obviously when you
have a beard,
facial recognition programs have a little
more difficulty recognizing how far
the jaw reaches, okay?
Let's see it.
And 003 eh,  face.
Hey, yeah, face. Okay, I'm coming this way,
I'm coming this way. Imagine the
possibilities of this.
Okay. Okay. Au. And if you notice,
And if you notice,
wow, wow,
wow.
Okay, if you notice, what I was
doing is drawing up a
voice recognition to see which users
have permission for what. I didn't
understand that.
I mean, what do you mean,
which users have permission
for what things? I say this because right now I don't see
the relationship between...
Ah,
in principle I think that Webkit
speech doesn't. Webkit speech takes your audio,
sends it to Google's servers,
probably the Google server will
know who you are, but it doesn't return that
information, it doesn't return the identity,
like for example Siri, okay? that
only the owner of the iPhone can
say, "Hey, Siri, wait, maybe... Okay
, okay, good." Yes, yes, correct. With
this library, the web one, which is
Google speech, right? Because it doesn't return the
identity, probably with a more
advanced one or with  some that does
recognize that and that there are First you would have to
train it, okay? So that it
recognizes your voice with respect to others.
Well yes. And then and then there's another there's
another library.
Okay, perfect.
Now the same
but for eh body.
Okay. So what happens? Well what
happens, let's see, is that you, for
example, can use these libraries
to know if there's someone in front of the
camera, okay? And to say, for
example, that the application locks
when someone disappears from the
camera, that is, close an automatic,
okay?
Body body. So now I'm coming over here,
I'm going to body, okay?
And now pay attention because if I get up for a
moment I'm
going to leave myself here.
Okay, it
basically recognizes the talas. Okay, it
recognizes the main part of the face.
And as you can see, and as you can see, as you can see,
Mediapipe, which is a Google project, well,
as I told you, with some
fairly minimal scripts, okay? With some
fairly simple scripts,  They allow you
not only for the computer to see you, okay?
But they allow the computer to
analyze things. And I'm telling you, for
example, with your posture or with, I
mean, if the facial mesh is picking up on you, you
can detect, for
example, what we were talking about
last year, Fran, that the computer,
let's say, detects your mood. Or
if it detects that a user is
hunched over or if it detects that they have a rather
sad facial expression, it might
change the colors of the
application to brighter ones or it might tell you
an audio message, "Hey, come on,
man, you can relax, okay?"
And
in the same way, we can do
anything. So, as I said,
natural interfaces,
this whole part of generating
natural user interfaces
is about showing you the new
trends in generating user interfaces
, because
user interfaces, well, then in
point three, it goes back to creating
visual components, whether buttons,
radios, or  switches, which if I do
n't know what, I don't know how many, but at
least we have a first, or rather,
sorry, a second unit that is a
little more futuristic and is pretty cool
because the exercises we can do
. Okay. Yes, correct, exactly. But the
idea is that it is not a
top-secret technology that is only available to
car manufacturers, but the
technology is already implemented in
web browsers. Obviously, for the
user to capture the camera, they have to
give you permission. Of course,
but we can do it. We can do it.
Good. And now, and now, uh, within
this part here, within this
unit number one, a moment, okay?
within this unit number one, which is
tools for
machine learning, there I'm going to have to
jump into Python for a moment because,
well, I want to show you a
tool that I'm sure some of you already
use because you tried it
last year, which is Oyama, okay?
So, Oyama is a tool that is
installed on, let's see it for a
moment,
okay? or called is  A tool that is
installed on MacOS, Windows, or Linux.
In this case, I have it installed
on Linux, and once
you have it,
the following happens, okay? Uh, Oyama
Oyama check version,
the Oyama for Windows. By the way, I do
n't know if I have it
installed here, I don't think so. Okay. Uh, just so
you know, it's much nicer than the one I'm
going to show you. I have the one for
Linux, but my son downloaded
the one for Windows and played around with it
one afternoon and had fun. It
basically consists of downloading an
artificial intelligence locally. If with
voice and speech we have given the computer a voice and hearing
,
if with parts and movements, then we have
made it able to see and recognize us. The
idea with this part is to make it
able to, let's say, understand us, okay? That
our computer has a little bit of
artificial intelligence, okay? So,
001 Oyama
MD check. And the first thing I'm going to do is
type Oyama version. What Oyama do I
have?
In this case  I have, okay, 011, whatever
. Okay. Next, okay?
Version, okay? Okay. Now I want to know
or call
eh check
installed
engines, let's say. They're not engines, they're
models. Okay, models. Exactly. Very good.
Oyama list.
And let's see what I have. If I go to
Oyama list. It
tells me, "Look, you have these,
you have the 20-byte GPT OSS, which
blows my RAM, this one doesn't even
occur to me.
And then you have the Quencoder, right?  And he
calls instruct, the quen encoder to
make code and he calls instruct,
right?  I'm going to put this on you.
Okay, let's assume,
let's assume that I love myself for a moment,
okay.
Let's suppose
I want to install this.  Oh, sorry.
Dis this.
Okay, so it would be this here,
install a new model,
okay?  And now, and now is where
the scary part comes,
because I say,
I say this, okay?
I say, eh, okay, now please
eh, send
question and get answer
on command line.
Okay, so here we go.
Let's see it.
I'm going to run this.  And what is it?
The capital of Spain.
Let's see it.  I run,
I run,
I run.
Think a little, think a little, think
a little,
think a little and keep thinking.  Let's
see how my processor works.
My processor will be there as soon as I
hit you.  Ah, look, that's where it ended.
The capital of Spain is Madrid.  Okay.  And
now next I say, okay.  And what
is the capital of Let's see, wait
a minute, wait a minute, wait a
minute.  Now, now let's get to it.  It's
Ah, cheaper on a VPS to pay for a
low-priced API.
I don't think so.  I don't think so.
And now I'll tell you, now I'll tell you, I'll
tell you why.  Look, uh, what's the
capital of uh France?  Okay, so you
can see that
we're going to see it.
Hey, I've entered, but he's ignoring
me quite a bit.  Hello, hello,
from France.
Okay, and let's look at the processor.  Wow,
right on.  Okay, fine.
Let's see, Fran.
Well, the point is that it depends on
what the use is because
if it's going to be for simple things, then
obviously paying for an API like
Open or a low-priced one like Gemini,
can be good.  However, look,
the exercises I'm going to give you,
which you'll start receiving
shortly,
have the following:  I have a project here
called EVAL.
The Eval project has activities for
all students.  For now I've
started with first grade.
So what happens?  Well, I come in
here
and if we look at the prompt, in the prompt I
am taking everything that is worth it, everything I
know about the student, I am taking,
I am sending him in the prompt
of everything about the entire subject.  I
'm sending you in the prompt, I
'm sending you in the prompt
exercises that we've done and I'm
clear, there are a lot of tokens, that's where I want to
get to, okay?  And ultimately, and
ultimately, it generates a
prompt.  What's going on?  Well, if you
start multiplying the tokens
in this question and answer
by the number of activities I've
generated, and mind you, it's been two weeks,
okay?  I mean, imagine the
entire course, well of course, the price per
token, although it's very cheap in
public APIs, would skyrocket.
So, that's why I'm telling you, for
example, in this specific case, within
that, for example, using the
GPT Chat API, well, it would give me questions and
answers of much higher quality,
obviously, because let's be clear and that
is that the power, the quality of the
response to the prompt, that is, a
model installed on my computer, well, it will
never have even remotely the quality
that Openi has for obvious reasons,
but nevertheless in terms of cost, I think
that although the processor then goes to
100, but okay, for example, look, or
call run,
explain to me
how to connect from PHP to MySQL,
okay?  And trick tri,
okay?  And this is, I insist,
running
on my computer.  And note that, in fact,
this model doesn't consume that much RAM or
processor, a little, but it's okay.
Well, my recommendation,
I insist, within the fact that
Fran is obviously there and then we'll see.  Ah, okay, okay,
okay,
okay.  Yes, no, no, be careful.  That
would also have to be looked at, since in this case
we are running it on our
computers, which are powerful, so it would have to be
tested on a VPS.  Well
yes,
I insist, we would have to see it.  You'd have to
see it.  And another thing, And another thing I'm
telling you is that with a VPS the most that
could happen is that by hiring a
cheaper VPS it would be slower.  It would be necessary to
see what the desired response speed is
.  And I, above
all, tell you that what I always
want is a matter of independence.  Mind you
, I have
n't been independent about this voice and speech issue
.
I rely on Google's Webkit speech API
, okay?  I don't
like it at all, but it's the closest thing I
have so far to being
independent in body parts and movements
.  I also depend on the
Mediapipe library which is from Google,
okay?  I'm not happy about it, but
this little script is the closest I
have right now.  It's like using an
external API, in fact,
to be independent.
We can use Gemini Open APIs,
whatever, okay?  But what
we have here is the closest thing to being
independent.  Clear.  Whose call is it?
Well, the model is called Meta.  The goal is
the United States, so in the end
we are dependent on it, okay?  Who is from
Alibaba, Alibaba, a Chinese company, we
still depend on someone.  There's a
model called ALIA, it's a
Spanish model that I'm waiting to try out a
bit
[Music]
to try not to depend on
others, okay?  from external factors,
but oh well.  So ultimately,
ultimately, the idea, let's see, okay?
Yes, correct.  And the idea, mind you, is to have
an independent AI locally.  And
then what Fran is mentioning,
when we talk about local, we're
talking about installing it on a
server
that provides internet service and
from there, okay?, we can
have a GPT micro chat.  Let's do
a GPT micro chat.
To make a GPT micro chat,
let's see.
I say, I say, ok, perfect.  I would like
to make a GPT micro chat.
Uh, using
a
backend in Python
calling Oyama eh
and using flask
frontend
HTML CSS JS and using fetch
to communicate
with the backend,
so we're going to have a front end
made in HTML, CSS and JavaScript that will
send information to a back end and the back end
in Python could be in any other
technology, okay?  It could be PHP, it could
be 9JS,
eh, it's going to communicate with Oyama to
pass him the question, get the
answer and throw it up.  Okay?   Let's
go there.   Let's
go there.
Look, Miguel Ángel, yes, but I can't
categorically assure you 100% that
it will work.  We know, we
know that we know nothing.  That is,
we know we have GPT chat,
but we don't know what's
behind it, they don't tell us.  Over
time.  It seems to me that
when I ask him in English, he seems to
understand me better.  And mind you,
I'm not a native English speaker, okay?
But speaking broken English I
feel like I get better
results than in Spanish,
but I don't know if that's a perception that
maybe was true last year and maybe
that's changed and I haven't noticed,
because the GPT chat changes and
then there are times when you ask something
late at night and it gives you some
[ __ ] great answers and
then you ask it something in the morning and it
curses you and it's like it's in
lazy mode, you know?  It's just that nobody
really knows what's behind it, you know?
From GPT Chat.  So yes, okay,
I do it for that reason, but I can't categorically assure you
that it works 100%
well.  So, let's create a
backend.
Let's create a frontend.
Careful.
Okay, let's create an HTML index on the
frontend.
Let's create a JS app.   We
are going to create a CSS style
and in the backend we are going to create an
appunp.
Okay, with that said, in app.p
we're going to put this which is basically
Python calling oyama.
And in the frontend we are going to put
index.html.  html,
which is the structure of the GPT microch,
the JS to collect the data and send it
and the frontend JS which are the styles.
Okay, if this is true,
if this is true.  Okay, this is
clear.  This is clear.  Okay, there you go,
damn it.  Let's do this.
Let's see.  Dam second, interfaces,
generation,
learning, exercises, micro, backend.
Let's open a terminal.
We're going to create an environment that leaves me a
little.  Anyway, let's create an environment
and activate the environment.  Let's see.  And
no, no.  Just a moment, just a moment, just a
moment.  No, no, no, no.  Now, now I'll
tell you that.  I'll tell you that now.  A
second one, which is a good question.
Let's see.
Your exercises are not yet available.   I'm
telling you too, I started with the
first graders and now I'll tell you,
okay?  And that's it.  So we
go to port 5000,
local host 2.5,000
and we have a GPT micro chat.  So
GPT microchat, uh, what is the capital
of Spain?
We ship
and
the capital of Spain is Madrid.  Okay.
Hm.  What is the difference between a
dog and a cat?
I'm going to see the processor.
Let's see how the processor will respond
to this.  Okay, shipping
and shipping.  Oh, okay, wait, he's
thinking.  Okay, the processor doesn't really
care either.  The model is not
bad at all.  I [ __ ] in the sea.  And this came out
of here, okay?  He's
paying me back in Mark.  Then nothing happens
because I can implement a library
that transforms from Mark to
In fact, my fan is starting to be heard
, but I don't know why, because
the CPU, as you can see, hasn't
changed much either, okay?  And this is the
question.  Sure, what's going on?  Well,
if this is the case, let's see which is the best
programming language.
Well, always keeping in mind that when
I'm sending this question, it's not being
sent to an external Open-type API
, okay?  but
the computer is calculating it, my
own computer is calculating it.  And then what
Fran said, that it's a matter of analyzing it,
it's a matter of studying it, well, what's
less difficult for me.  Okay, Fran,
one criterion is that, one criterion is
how much it costs me,
but I insist, I always insist on the
same thing.  I implant an
artificial intelligence in a client
and today I depend on, you know?
From an external AI, from an API that at
any moment to Open or Donald
Trump, I'm always with the same thing,
okay?  I don't know, but they're going crazy
and either they multiply the price by 10 and
remain so cool, or
Donald Trump suddenly says, "Look, now
we're going to impose tariffs on
artificial intelligence."  Because?  Well, because I
woke up like this this morning, okay?  Or
suddenly he comes to the United States and
says, "Well, now we're going to secure
our global hegemony and
artificial intelligence, and we're going to cut off service to the
rest of the world."  And I tell you,
that would have been unthinkable in other
times, but not in this one.  In this era,
whether you like it or not, anything is
possible.  Okay?  That's why I tell you that yes,
we can
have independence; if we can avoid
depending on external factors, then all the
better.
Okay, let's talk about the
topic of evaluations, okay?   They
are not yet available.
We'll talk on Thursday about the
evaluations for second year.  I'm
starting with the first one, but I
can start teaching it to you
now.  Look,
I'll tell you later that when you
start entering the evaluations starting Thursday, we'll
enter at eval.jocarsa.com.
Within eval.jocarsa.com
First, you will enter the ID that you
gave me in the preferences form.
Okay?  So I'm going to take the ID of a
first-year student, I'm going to click
continue, and then I'm going to see the
subjects this student is
enrolled in.
So next I'm going to go to
programming, for example, and I'm going to
continue.
From here, a series of
units appear in which there are activities
to carry out.  For example, I want to
talk about selection structures or
repetition structures, I don't know.
Okay?  I then click
continue.  Okay, and an activity is proposed
specifically for this
student.  This student has stated that one
of her hobbies is walking in the countryside.
So the statement of the application
is in a world full of adventures, each
of us has our own rhythm.
Imagine you're on a grand expedition
into the countryside, exploring magical trails and
encountering wonderful animals in the
wild.  But before you start,
you need to classify yourself by age to
make sure you're ready for this
new stage, okay?  So I create a
program that starts by entering data
and tells us age equals input, age
equals convert it.  Okay.  And now,
use
selection structures to classify
participants by age,
adapting to their pace and enjoying
different activities.  Restrictions.
Don't use functions or classes.  Keep everything
in one control structure.
And the student, I have to rethink this activity
, okay?  Because I'm almost
done with the activity, but
well, this shouldn't be like this, but
okay, let's see another one.  Wait a minute,
let's look at jump or
selection structures, shall we?  You're on repeat,
okay?  And okay, look, for example, this one.
Use a for loop that iterates from
1 to 30. In each iteration it
increments the value of days explored and
displays the phrase on the screen, "Today is
day X in the field."  Okay?  This is what's
going to happen, and what's going to
happen is that on this platform, for
example, we're once again proposing a
natural field activity.  In others that we have
seen later, earlier,
today, board games were proposed
, which was another hobby of this student,
so board game activities were proposed to her
, right?  So, from
here on, an activity is proposed for you to
do.
A series of restrictions may be proposed to you below
, okay?  You cannot
use variables that have not been
explained in class.  The loop must be a for
loop.  The variable must start with
the value zero.  Okay?  And you are told, and
now we are going to this, what are the
evaluation criteria, okay?  How you
should answer and how you should complete
the activity.
This is what I was telling you, and what
we were discussing before, Fran, and that is that to
do this activity, the
artificial intelligence I have
installed has explored everything I've
explained in that kind of
selection structures and has generated an
activity.  But of course, if at first
you can imagine that the code is
very simple and you've already seen what
took up a prompt, imagine what
that prompt will take up in a second.  I mean, the
second thing you're seeing is that
obviously,
okay, moment, you're seeing that there
's obviously a lot more code
just with what we did in the
previous class, multimedia.
So, notice that as soon as I add
animation, what it's going to do is
eat all these exercises.
Maybe it literally takes half an hour
to do an exercise for
each of you, but I don't care.  Okay,
the point is that it might take
half an hour, but hey, a computer that
's on and consuming
electricity, that's perfectly clear.
But if I enter that prompt into Chat
GPT, I know that it will still cost me €1 for
each exam, that is, €1 for each activity and I
have to give each student a bag of
activities multiplied
by x students.  Okay?  That's why I tell you
that
if there was a prompt that I know that you
know is going to be what the capital of
Madrid is, well I would tell you, "[ __ ], I'll
call the GBT Chat API and I can
send thousands of questions that might
charge me 20 cents, but for example
here we have a case in which they do
n't."  Okay?  How do you fill out this
activity?  Let's go for it.
To fill in that activity.
Next we will see.  Well, first
let's read.  And he wants to register every
day.  Day counter, days
explored.  It varies.  Loop to
explore.  A for loop that has such a thing.  In
each iteration, days explored.  Today is
day X in the field.  Okay, I'm clear about
what I have to do.  So
next step number one.  Step
number one.  I write the code.  I'm going to
IDEl.
I'm going to IDEl.
I make a new file.
Hey!  Careful.  I make a new file.
I go to desktop
and say, eh, activity, calm activity,
okay?  And I say and I say, let's see,
create a variable called days
explored.
days explored
is equal to zero.  Okay.  Okay.  Loop to
explore.  So I iterate
from 1 to 30
for days in range from 0 to
31, okay?  From the 1st to the 31st,
sorry.
And I say, in each iteration increase
the value of days explored by one.  In
each iteration
I increase the value of 10 explored + 1,
okay?  And then I say and it shows on the
screen.  Today is the day X of the field.
Print.  Print.
Today is day X of the field and I say
STR, conversion of type
days explored.  Okay?  Okay.  With this,
as you can see, what I'm doing is
strictly following what the
activity is telling me.  Following.
X is the current number, okay?  At the
end of the book, it displays on the screen
the sentence, "I have explored the field for
a total of y days. where print
where the value of y is the final value
of days explored
and that's it. Restrictions. I can't
use variables or structures. Okay,
the loop must be for type, okay? The
variable explored starts at
zero. Okay, I comply. Okay, I have complied. So
below
I have the code and here below it says your
answer. But I shouldn't
copy this code and paste it here yet, right?
What I have to do is read the
evaluation rubric. Where is the
evaluation rubric? Let's see it. The
evaluation rubric is at
githahub.com/jocarsa/documentos.
Here you have a guide for solving, guide
for solving, simulation, simulation,
simulation. Okay, there are a lot of
guides and simulations on how to solve
this activity, but I'm going to go to the
evaluation rubric. And the
evaluation rubric tells me, first make a
brief introduction and  Contextualization.
Okay, so I say,
what was this exercise about? This
exercise was about
repetition structures, okay? Brief introduction and
contextualization.
Explain the concept clearly and
correctly.
Repetition structures allow us to get
the computer or the program to repeat
a series of instructions so that we humans don't
have to
manually repeat all that code.
Mention what it's for or in what
context it's used. Repetition loops
allow us to
save work
and be more productive.
Okay, that's it. Okay, part one.
Next question.
Point two,
detailed and precise development. Include
correct and complete definitions.
Appropriate technical terminology, explain how it
works step by step, and give
real examples.
When we create a forum structure,
first of all,
we indicate or use
the reserved word for.
Next,
we create a variable,
establish a range,
and use a colon
to indicate the beginning
of instructions.
And I say quote, quote, quote. It's
quote, quote, quote, this is
code in Markdown. And I say for day in
range of  0 to 31. Okay, I'll put a small
sample
and say, "And then
using uh the indentation we
specify
the operations
to repeat,
like for example in this code
quote, quote, quote, quote, quote
, quote." and I say for day in
range
and I say print.
Today is day comma day comma of the month,
okay? A simple example of a for
control structure in Python,
okay? Practical application.
Okay. And then I say
And then I say, to
better show the concept that we want to
illustrate,
below
we can find a complete example
in which a for loop iterates and modifies
a variable
declared
before. of the loop itself. And then
now
is when I take that code,
copy it and paste it. This is the
complete exercise, include a clear example with
real code. Okay? And finally, a
brief conclusion.
Brief conclusion.
As we have seen,
for control structures or
loop control, if you will, are very
powerful
because with just a few lines of code they
allow us to build programs
that perform
multiple copies of a task or
multiple  executions or multiple
occurrences of a task. Okay,
finally, finally,
delete the titles. I've put the titles
as a guide so we know we're
solving the evaluation rubric
step by step.
We remove the titles.
We take the code, the text, okay? We
paste it
and send it. And we send it.
And that's it.
The response has been saved
correctly. And that's how you
'll have to
fill out the activities starting Thursday. If I now
go to the server,
if I now go to the server,
I go to
the Eval folder, where
that application is published.
I go to Eval, I go to activities, I'm
going to see the last modified one.
The last modified one today at 8:30
and uh, I'm going to load it in the text editor
here. Okay, I'm going to load it
and then we'll see that a
JSON file is saved. Every time you
send an activity, that
activity is saved in a
JSON file
and the repetition structures appear,
allowing the program to create, I don't
know what, I don't know how many. This was
sent from IP address such and such on date,
the student's ID is obviously such
and such, okay? And that's it.
This is how the activities are submitted.
Yes, yes, no problem because I'll
restart Serena's exercise later.
Okay, so let's see, Miguel
Ángel, I'll answer that now. Okay,
next question. Next question,
before we get to the point about
scoring, which you'll see now that you don't have to
worry about. In fact, I came back
from first grade to explain this very thing, so you'll
see now.
Of course, Fran, imagine that
starting this weekend, I
have a small
artificial intelligence application that
gives each of
you activities according to your preferences, okay?
Personalized activities. I'm going to have
another artificial intelligence, which is the
same thing. I mean, it's a
Python skip that goes against Oyama, but that
goes through all of them and  Each of those
Joneses,
and you tell him, look, this is the
question statement, this is what
the student answered, evaluate it,
okay? Evaluate it, give it a grade from 0
to 10, and give it feedback. In other
words, tell him if he did it right, and if he didn't
, then tell him what he should have done
to do it right, based on, in other
words, what should he have done to
do it right? Based on the
evaluation rubric, which I'm also going to
provide, okay? So, as you
can imagine, he'll spend
hours evaluating, and the amount of
tokens consumed will be incredible, but it doesn't
matter. Since it's local, I'm not
too worried about it beyond
obviously the processor time I
used and the electricity it
consumes, which in this case will probably
be in the early hours of Saturday to
Sunday, so I'll just leave it there calculating
and that's it. Okay,
let's see, the activities can be carried out
with what you correct us. In
principle, it's not  Expected, but hey, I'm
not going to refuse, okay? I mean, we can
design the system so you can
respond. That is, if the system
tells you, "Look, you got a seven, and
to get a 10 you should have
done this," well, hey, you can
do it, okay?  I mean, my goal isn't for you to
get it right the first time, my
goal is for you to get it right in the end.
The activities could be
redone, I have to see.  The exam
couldn't be retaken, okay?  But okay,
but the activities yes.  Why do I say
the exam?  For a very simple reason,
what I just explained to you
is how
subunit activities, unit activities, and
quarterly exams are resolved.
Everything will be in exactly this same
format, which means that once
you get used to the evaluation rubric, you'll
have it for the entire course.
for the entire course in my subjects.
I mean, Pilar Ruiz and Alicia's
are a different story, okay?  So, that
means that on the first day it's going to
take you a while to get used to the
assessment rubric and to see what they ask me in
this block and to see what they ask me in this
other block, but once
we have that done, it's just repeating this same
scheme for any assessment in
this course, okay?  Respond this
way and you get the highest grade and that's it.
Let's talk about penalties or
let's talk about how it's evaluated,
let's say, when you submit, so to speak,
late, okay?  So for that,
in my in my in my these documents, in
my GitHub of documents, you
also have a
penalty policy, okay?  and the
penalty policy, in addition to having
the penalty calculation here,
but it's okay because you have an
illustrative table and I think with the
illustrative table you'll see it well.
If you submit the activity
within 24 hours of the
activity being posted, the maximum score is 10.
If you submit it between one and
two days later, of course, a
tenth of a point is subtracted, which means you can grade it out of
9.9.  That activity would have a maximum of
9.9.
If you deliver 2-3 days later,
9.8, what happens?  If you hand this in,
I think it's 7 days, okay?  It seems to me.
Well, 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
Submitting the activity a week late
only takes away 0.6.
Submit the activity 10 days later.
10 days later remove a stitch.
What does that mean?  Well,
nothing's wrong, okay?  If you deliver the
following week, during the
following week, then you have a 9.4, you score
out of 9.4 and whoever delivers
immediately, then that person scores
out of 10.
If you deliver two weeks later,
two weeks later you score out of eight,
that is, 15 days late and still
scores out of eight.  Of course, the one that is
delivered like three months later, well that
one obviously scores out of one,
right?  Whoever submits a month and a half
later will score out of two.
Obviously, the one that is submitted months
later, because that one obviously cannot be
scored.  Okay, that's it.
And this is the evaluation policy.  And
finally, I have to
explain the
percentages to you, okay?  What
each activity weighs.  For that, I think I have
the percentages here,
which are the following ones that I am showing you here
.
You will have three types of activities:
subunit exams,
easy ones, which are 20% of the
quarterly grade.
Unit activities, the not-so-
easy ones, the less easy ones, which are
20% of the quarterly grade.
the quarterly exam,
which is 50% of the quarterly grade.
And then since 20 + 20 + 50 do not add up to 100,
but add up to 90, we have 10% of the
extra mile.  The extraile is a project of
yours that I haven't included, a
project that isn't included anywhere in
the course.  It's a project that
you do because you wanted to, and
I don't tell you what to
do.  You decide what you have to
do in that project.  Obviously,
this project must use the
knowledge of the subject, of
course.
And that free, independent,
self-initiated project, that project is the
10% extra mile, the extra mile,
let's say.
And this is this is the percentage of the
quarterly evaluation, okay?
So that's it, don't worry too much about
the
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.  Uh, no, no, no, no
, no.  Not for you.  Wait, wait.
Let's see.
The project is like the FCTs
we discussed at the beginning of the
class, and it's that those students who are going through
low, the old education law,
you go through, sorry, low or yes it was low,
I think, I don't remember, anyway, whatever.
You're going for a TFG,
the TFG is evaluated, okay?  The TFG
is a project that you carry out together with the
FCTs from March
to June.
And this TFG is evaluated with a single grade
with the final presentation and the submission of the
project.  I'll send you the TFG index
shortly.  I have it here on Google
Drive.
In fact, in fact, if you give me your email, I
can share it with you right now.
So, uh, TFG,
TFG Dow, which is the same, right?  And
I share it with you.  And this is the index.  Here's
the index of the TFG, okay?
lifelong, old-fashioned.
Yes, correct.  Yes, exactly.  Okay, a
functional app with everything
we've given.  Indeed.  Okay, give me
your email and use the chat here and I'll share it with you
.
Okay.  And
the TCG, for those of you on the
old plan, doesn't have quarters, it's the third
quarter and that's it.  Perfect.  Well, I'll
share it with you as a reader, okay?  And there
you have it.  And throughout these months we
will be talking about how to approach the TFG.
And for those of you who are going to
the LFP,
instead of a TFG, you have an itinerary, I was going
to say, you have an intermodular project 2,
which you already know how we started with the
index and such, you're welcome.  And that one does go
by quarters.
And the intermodular project is assessed the
same as the rest of the subjects with
safety activities.  activities
per unit and quarterly exam,
okay?  And there's a bit of a problem there
because those with the old plan go to one
topic and those with the new plan go to another
topic.  Another thing, another thing that I
can offer you if you want, okay, Miguel
Ángel?  It's that although for example, the
issue of TFG and F, that is, the issue of FCTs,
of course, Agustín, there is no TCG, but there is an
intermodular project, which ends up being the
same.  The only thing
is that before the TFG was done three months
at a time and now the
inter-nuclear project is done little by little
from the beginning, but in the end it's the
same.  Okay?  So, Miguel Ángel, I
can't change the FCTs for you
because you have to go from
March to June.  Now, the topic of the
intermodular project or the TFG, whatever
you want, because in the end the
intermodular project is a TFG, okay?  So,
yes, exactly.  And I'm telling you, in this case,
mind you, I'm also going to tell you something,
Miguel Ángel, in this case where we're
talking about distance learning,
the issue of dosed practices, I
think it's phenomenal, okay?  Now, in other
institutes where they teach in person it's
hell, okay?  That's not practical
because I can tell you,
guys, that in the morning you go
to practice for a few hours and in the afternoon you go to
classes.  Well, there you have it, the
distance learning mode.  But of course, in the mornings,
that is, those in person who go
to class in the morning, having each one have a
calendar is outrageous.  Okay, but
anyway, what I'm telling you is,
think about it and if you want, do a TFG and if
not, do an intermodular project.  And if you
sign up for an intermodular project, well, in the
end I'll evaluate it as a TFG and that's it.
Okay, the extra, but it's not extra smile, it
's extra mile, it's the extra mile, not the
extra smile, okay?  They are effectively the ones who
actually have the
knowledge given in that quarter
for that subject, right?  And then the
intermodular project is actually
a whole, right?  It is, I insist, what
we are seeing on Fridays, okay?  Which
is the project where we first
analyze the companies, decide what
type of company we want, look at the
competition, what its structure is, all of
that, okay?  We are following an index,
both the people who do it as a TFG
and the people who do it
as an intermodular project, it's the
same.  I mean, if you look at the
index of the traditional TFG, it's a
collection of information, companies
in the sector based on their characteristics,
identification of needs, the same thing,
right?  So, that's why I say that what
they've done with the intermodular project
has basically been to take the old
TFG index from the BOE and simplify it
a little, but it's basically still the
same.  That's why I'm telling you it's
okay because in the end, okay?, the
work you're going to do is going to be
practically the same.  Good.  And before it
gets any later, well yes, yes, yes,
yes, correct.  There are extra thousand for
intermodular project.  What does it consist of?   I'll
tell you about it on Friday when
we get to the intermodular project, but
yes, there is one, there is one.  Correct.
Okay.  And eh, let's see, let's see if you
've sent me resumes.  I hope so
, to send this to the company.
Okay, so we go here and Okay.  Okay,
let's see, Agustín.  Okay, just a moment.
Let's create a folder, okay?  CV and
then I will upload it to Google Drive.  Luis,
yes, please.  Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, please.
Let's see, let's see.  Augustine
this way.  Fran, this way.  Holy crap, there are two of them.
Fran, what do we do?
Which shipment?
Oh, okay, maybe it's a PDF and a
link to Google Drive.  Okay, it's the
same one.  Okay, okay, great.  Perfect.
Okay.  Okay, okay, okay.  Let's see the
WhatsApp.
Okay, let's see.
And let's see.
Okay, okay, Luis, I'll see you around here,
okay?  So, OK.
Okay.
Mentín.
Come on, Luis, give me
a resume.
Let's see.
Ah, by email.  Okay, okay.  There it is.
Well, let's see, let's see, eh, it's difficult,
okay?  It's difficult for me to give you a
recommendation for the simple reason
that this is the first year that we're
doing Intermodular Project 2 and I haven't
experienced the development yet, that is, I haven't
experienced a full year of
Intermodular Project 2. So yes, I have
experienced a lot of years of TCG and I've
seen that, well, when students
leave everything to the last minute, they
end up doing nothing during the
term, it always happens and they
don't sleep in the last week.
The intermodular project seems
better to me because there are
activities, there are assessments, and in
some way the student is forced,
but that's good for the student, you
know?  to work little by
little and work hard and not
have that frenzy of
writing and submitting the TFG in the last week before June
, okay?  No matter how many
milestones and intermediate deliveries I give you and
all that, in the end people skip them
and end up submitting their TFG in a hurry at the
end.  Okay?  So, having said
that, I would recommend you join the
intermodular project, but as I
said, I've seen
the pros and cons of the TFG over the years, and I still
need to see the pros and
cons of the intermodular project this year.  Maybe we'll
finish Intermodular Project 2 this year
and I'll never miss
the Final Project again, and maybe we'll finish this year and
say, "Oh my God, with the
Final Project going so well, why did they give us the
Intermodular Project?"  Don't know.  I don't know how to
give you an answer right now.
Do you know
well?  So, then let's go there.  I'm going
to send.  Oh, look, Joshua.  Very good,
perfect.  Let's go there.  Okay, this way.
Very good.  Okay, so let's send out
these resumes.
I have them all now, okay?  And I'm going
to give this one a star, okay?  And here we go
with the internship students.
Very good.  Well,
hello
Raquel.
Thank you very much for your email.
You've welcomed us students these past two years, and the
experience
so far has been very positive,
so I'm glad you're
contacting me again for this
course.
This course is special.
As you may know,
due to the new
vocational training regulations,
students no longer do the
400-hour internship.
Gee, uh, from March
to June, okay?  And okay, yes, please,
pass it on,
pass samples to Miguel Ángel, but I'm
telling you, Miguel Ángel, wait, now,
now I'll tell you things, okay?  What
is important is that we also talk a little
about the CV, apart from you
sending him, okay?, samples of yours
from March to June, eh, but
those 400 hours are spread out over
the course
from more or less until the end of
May.
This means that, if you
want it or wish it that way,
you can count on the students already in the
company
without having to wait until March as
in previous courses.
Attached to this email I am sending you an
initial DCV series of students.  Since
we're in class this afternoon,
I didn't want to
leave the
CV collection for later, but rather, the sooner we
can close this matter, the better.
And if you want, check them out
and tell me something when you can.
I assume
you will interview
the candidate
who interests you
to fill the internship position.
I look forward to hearing from you
when you can.  Greetings, José
Vicente.
And with that, I then
take the CVs.  And as I was saying at the
beginning of the class, before this
contact, before this opportunity
cools off, we send out our
resumes, okay?  And if someone sends it to me
later, then it's no big deal.  Then you
attach another email and another
resume and that's it.  Okay.
Okay.  Come on, let's go this way.  This is
sent here so that things don't take any longer
.  And I'll tell you about the
curriculum, okay?  I'm going to tell you the
same thing I told you last year, it's not going to
be anything new, but
we'll see.  Uh, a resume has
three parts.  One, personal data.
Two, uh, work experience
in that order and three, training.
Okay?
In your work experience and
training,
highlight the technologies
you use in bold.
Okay, when someone opens your
resume, the first thing that jumps out at them
, okay? Whether it's JavaScript,
PHP,
Python,
SQL,
[ __ ], etc., okay?  That's the first thing
you have, because when you send a
programmer's resume, what
people want to see when you send your resume is
that you program, right?  So, let
that be clearly visible in bold, right
there, okay?
If you don't have any work experience, which
some of you will tell me you don't, or if it's not
related to the subject, then you can include
the internships you
did in the intermediate level
and those from the first year of DAM.
That is, it is a resume for a
programmer.
So, first of all,
always put everything that has to do
with programmer, okay?  And then
and then the rest.
Same thing in training, okay?  First,
computer training.
You haven't finished the cycle, okay?  put
I'm doing the cycle, okay?  And then
the rest, the first thing that has to be seen
on the resume is what you have as a
programmer.
Personal data.
Add social media,
including LinkedIn
and GitHub, because companies will
want to see what you're up to, and
companies will want to see your
code.
If your LinkedIn isn't in order, you
're already running to get it in order.
If your Jidhamb is not in order, you
are already running to get it in order.
Because all of this, for example, Jithub
last year was to show me,
this year it's for
companies to see and for them to take you on as an
intern and tomorrow for them to
take you on as a contract, okay?
And that's it.  and there's no more mystery and
today is please create, that is, make a
cool design, okay?  A nice design,
but use Canva, I mean, I'm not going to
take a look to see what I find.
I'm scared, but anyway, let's see what
happens.  Let's see, Agustín.  Okay, okay.
Come on, very well.  Okay.  Okay, okay, okay, okay
, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay
, okay, okay.  No.
Ah, fantastic.  Well, it's already
sent, but hey, send me another one
then.
Okay, well no, dude, Agustín, I mean,
last year you did your
first-year internship, okay?  So, give me the
practices first.  And what did you do with
the internship?  And what if JavaScript and what if
the particles and what if the
neutron accelerator or
whatever, LinkedIn, okay?  But let it be a
link, let it be a link and this way,
okay?  Okay, okay, okay.
No, man, I mean, how do you turn me on?  I mean, at the
very bottom, it almost falls off the
page, right?  The senior technician
application is that this resume
is telling me, I mean, don't give me the
position, you know?   At
the top, the first thing is always the most
important, and at the bottom, the last thing is the least
important.
Okay, this, OK.  Okay, this is fantastic.
If it's the experience you have, it's the
experience you have, that's it.  But
tell me about the practices you did
last year.  Let's see, Joshua.  Okay.  Okay,
very good.  Okay, okay, okay.  Okay,
mobile mail and all that.  Put me on LinkedIn, put me and
about me.  Passionate.  Okay.  Okay.  The
photo.  Cool.  Good.  Fresh green.  Okay, okay,
okay, okay.  In your case, last year, you did
n't do the internship,
so this year, by the way, you've accumulated
500 hours.  Well, that's it.  This is the
experience.  This is the experience.
Academic data, the cycle comes first.
Okay.  Okay.  Come on.
Ah, until the sixth semester.  Okay.  Okay.
Okay, come on.  Very well,
Luis.
Okay.  Wow, this resume has changed me
compared to last year.  Okay,
LinkedIn. Yeah, fantastic.  Look, Luis
Rodriguez, software developer,
specializing in applications.  Let's see,
this is what I say, okay?  technical skills,
right?  From JS, MySQL, PHP, this is going to blow your
mind.  I mean, the first thing that catches your
eye, I mean, you see this here and you see
this here and you say, "Okay, this person
programs."  That's it.  And from there
we continue.  Education first, the
DAM.  Very good.  Experience dependent.   Tacata tacata
.  Okay,
very good.  Projects, okay?  Well,
projects.  Okay, the repository and more
projects on Jitha and on my website.  Okay,
this is it.  Very good.  And here are
last year's practices.
Okay, Fran, let's see.  Okay, okay, very
good.
No, man, Fran, you're a
computer systems and network technician.  Okay, you are.
Okay, you have that degree, but whoever reads
this is going to say, "Oh, no, no, I'm
looking for a senior
development technician."  No, okay, you put
application development technician and then somewhere
below also put and I am also a
microcomputer and network systems technician
.  Okay, but this is, look, let's see.
Very good.  Okay.  Okay.  Uh, okay, okay.
Work experience.  Very good, very good.
Okay.  Okay.  The thing about the higher technician
in platform development at the
Polytechnic University.  Fantastic.  Very good.  This
is, okay, microcomputer systems technicians
, okay?  And
first officer.  Okay.  First the
programming stuff, and then the experiences or
training that have nothing to do with
programming.  Fantastic.  Okay.
Higher technical education, intermediate level
and school level.  Okay.
Additional information.  Okay.  Courses
related to Angular, Larabel,
E-commerce, JJO, Web.  Okay, fantastic.
And then Windows, Internet, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.  Okay, fantastic.
That is.  Okay, then nothing, your
resumes are fine.  Just
improve that issue, okay?  Just
improve the issue of you opening it and it
being a resume that jumps out at you
, you know?  Because you might say,
"Wow, it's very obvious that I put
Python, PHP, SQL there, but it's not
obvious, okay? Because the person who evaluates those
resumes evaluates those and 20 more,
because this girl is surely not the, I
mean, she didn't just send me an email, she's
surely sent an email to some
other institute, so it's not just going to be
you, there will be more
programming students competing for those
positions, okay? So, even though it's
obvious, but if a person opens that
resume because it has 30 more to see, well
as soon as they see that it doesn't fit, they
'll say, "On to the next one." Okay,
life is unfair, but I didn't
create it, okay? So that's how it
is. But if when they see the resume,
the first thing that jumps out at them is PHP,
Python, SQL, programmer, development,
well that person will say, "Wait, wait,
wait, I like this, let's keep
reading." Okay, it's a bit absurd,  But it
is what it is. I mean, it's definitely what it
is. So, that's it. So, that's it. So, that's
not much for today, not much because it
's 9:00. Theoretically, we have until
30:00, but this has caught us a
bit off guard to now get back
to interfaces and do more things, okay?
So, in the coming weeks, I'll
obviously be telling you all the details,
especially because the
next part of
this is augmented reality. But as
you can imagine, it's 9:00, so I
won't have time to explain
augmented reality to you from now until 9:30, okay? So, we'll
continue on Thursday. On Thursday
, you know, we'll work on
data access and processes and services, and then
on Friday, again, on the
intermodular project and business management systems
. Okay?
Well, guys,
we'll continue on Thursday.